Creasy's art is death, and he is about to paint his masterpiece.
Man on Fire is a action, drama, thriller film directed by Tony Scott.
Jaded ex-CIA operative John Creasy reluctantly accepts a job as the
bodyguard for a 10-year-old girl in Mexico City.
They clash at first, but eventually bond, and when she's kidnapped he's
consumed by fury and will stop at nothing to save her life.
John W. Creasy, played by Denzel Washington.
Lupita Ramos, played by Dakota Fanning.
Paul Rayburn, played by Christopher Walken.
Lisa Ramos, played by Radha Mitchell.
Samuel Ramos, played by Marc Anthony.
Miguel Manzano, played by Giancarlo Giannini.
Man on Fire is a 2004 action thriller film directed and produced by Tony Scott, with
a screenplay by Brian Helgeland and co-produced by Arnon Milchan.
It is based on the 1980 novel of the same name by A.
The film stars Denzel Washington and Dakota Fanning in lead roles, alongside Christopher Walken, Radha
Mitchell, Giancarlo Giannini, Marc Anthony, Rachel Ticotin and Mickey Rourke in supporting roles.
This adaptation shifts the setting from Naples, Italy, to Mexico City, diverging from the
earlier 1987 film version of Quinnell's novel, which was also produced by Milchan.
The film follows a despondent, alcoholic former CIA officer-turned-bodyguard, who embarks on a
violent revenge spree after a nine-year-old under his charge is kidnapped in Mexico City.
Man on Fire was released in the United States by
20th Century Fox on April 23, 2004.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $130 million
worldwide against a production budget of $60–70 million.
Fanning's performances earned her nominations for the Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best Young
Performer and the Young Artist Award for Best Leading Young Actress in a Feature Film.
Additionally, the film received 2 nominations at the 36th NAACP Image Awards –
Outstanding Motion Picture and Outstanding Actor in a Motion Picture (Washington).
The film explores themes of mexico, mexico city, mexico,
based on novel or book, kidnapping, bodyguard.
The tone is emotional and intense.